<calenhad>
    <metadata>
        <title>Complex Planet</title>
        <date>30 March 2018 22:02</date>
        <author>M C Bucknall, ported from libnoise complexplanet example</author>
        <description> This program demonstrates how to use the libnoise library to generate terrain elevations for a complex planetary surface that has the size of the earth.

            The terrain elevations are generated by a collection of over a hundred noise modules in a hierarchy of groups and subgroups.  Each group and subgroup outputs a single output value that originates from a caching module (noise::module::Cache).  Each group and subgroup can be thought of as a single complex noise module that can be used as a source module for other noise modules.  The caching module was chosen as the source of the output value to prevent costly recalculations by each group and subgroup requesting an output value from it.

            The following is a list of module groups and subgroups that buildAsync the planet's terrain:

            Group (continent variable)
            Subgroup (base continent variable)
            Subgroup (continent variable)
            Group (terrain type variable)
            Subgroup (terrain type variable)
            Group (mountainous terrain)
            Subgroup (mountain base variable)
            Subgroup (high mountainous terrain)
            Subgroup (low mountainous terrain)
            Subgroup (mountainous terrain)
            Group (hilly terrain)
            Subgroup (hilly terrain)
            Group (plains terrain)
            Subgroup (plains terrain)
            Group (badlands terrain)
            Subgroup (badlands sand)
            Subgroup (badlands cliffs)
            Subgroup (badlands terrain)
            Group (river positions)
            Subgroup (river positions)
            Group (scaled mountainous terrain)
            Subgroup (scaled mountainous terrain)
            Group (scaled hilly terrain)
            Subgroup (scaled hilly terrain)
            Group (scaled plains terrain)
            Subgroup (scaled plains terrain)
            Group (scaled badlands terrain)
            Subgroup (scaled badlands terrain)
            Group (final planet)
            Subgroup (continental shelf)
            Subgroup (base continent elevation)
            Subgroup (continents with plains)
            Subgroup (continents with hills)
            Subgroup (continents with mountains)
            Subgroup (continents with badlands)
            Subgroup (continents with rivers)
            Subgroup (unscaled final planet)
            Subgroup (final planet)

            A description of each group and subgroup can be found above the source code for that group and subgroup.

            Copyright (C) 2004, 2005 by Jason Bevins
            Translation to Calenhad CML 2017.
        </description>
    </metadata>
    <variables>
        <variable name="badlands_amount" value="0.03125">
            <notes>Determines the amount of badlands terrain that covers the planet. Values range from 0.0 (no badlands) to 1.0 (all terrain is covered in badlands.)  Badlands terrain will overlap any other type of terrain.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="badlands_lacunarity" value="2.21289">
            <notes>Lacunarity of the planet's badlands.  Changing this value produces slightly different badlands.  For the best results, this value should be random, but close to 2.0.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="badlands_twist" value="1">
            <notes>Specifies the "twistiness" of the badlands.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="carver_frequency" value="4.34375">
            <notes>Frequency of the planet's continents.  Higher frequency produces smaller, more numerous continents.  This value is measured in radians.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="continent_frequency" value="1">
            <notes>Frequency of the planet's continents.  Higher frequency produces smaller, more numerous continents.  This value is measured in radians.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="continent_height_scale" value="0.25">
            <notes>Scaling to apply to the base continent elevations, in planetary elevation units.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="continent_lacunarity" value="2.20898">
            <notes>Lacunarity of the planet's continents.  Changing this value produces  slightly different continents.  For the best results, this value should be random, but close to 2.0.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="hills_amount" value="0.75">
            <notes>Determines the amount of hilly terrain that appears on the planet. Values range from 0.0 (no hills) to 1.0 (all terrain is covered in hills).  This value must be less than MOUNTAINS_AMOUNT.  Because the  mountainous terrain will overlap parts of the hilly terrain, and  the badlands terrain may overlap parts of the hilly terrain, setting  HILLS_AMOUNT to 1.0 may not completely cover the terrain in hills.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="hills_lacunarity" value="2.16211">
            <notes>Lacunarity of the planet's hills.  Changing this value produces slightly  different hills.  For the best results, this value should be random, but  close to 2.0.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="hills_twist" value="1">
            <notes>Specifies the "twistiness" of the hills.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="mountain_glaciation" value="1.375">
            <notes>Specifies the amount of "glaciation" on the mountains.  This value should be close to 1.0 and greater than 1.0.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="mountain_lacunarity" value="2.14258">
            <notes>Lacunarity of the planet's mountains.  Changing this value produces slightly different mountains.  For the best results, this value should be random, but close to 2.0.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="mountains_twist" value="1">
            <notes>Specifies the "twistiness" of the mountains.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="moutains_amount" value="0.5">
            <notes>Determines the amount of mountainous terrain that appears on the planet.  Values range from 0.0 (no mountains) to 1.0 (all terrain is covered in mountains).  Mountainous terrain will overlap hilly terrain. Because the badlands terrain may overlap parts of the mountainous terrain, setting MOUNTAINS_AMOUNT to 1.0 may not completely cover the terrain in mountains.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="plains_lacunarity" value="2.31445">
            <notes>Lacunarity of the planet's plains.  Changing this value produces slightly  different plains.  For the best results, this value should be random, but  close to 2.0.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="river_depth" value="0.0234375">
            <notes>Maximum depth of the rivers, in planetary elevation units.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="sea_level" value="0">
            <notes>Specifies the planet's sea level.  This value must be between -1.0 (minimum planet elevation) and +1.0 (maximum planet elevation.)</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="shelf_level" value="-0.375">
            <notes>Specifies the level on the planet in which continental shelves appear. This value must be between -1.0 (minimum planet elevation) and +1.0 (maximum planet elevation), and must be less than SEA_LEVEL.</notes>
        </variable>
        <variable name="terrain_offset" value="1">
            <notes>Offset to apply to the terrain type variable.  Low values (less than 1.0) causethe rough areas to appear only at high elevations.  High values (greater than 2.0) cause the rough areas to appear at any elevation.  The percentage of rough areas on the planet are independent of this value.</notes>
        </variable>
    </variables>
    <legends>
        <legend type="gradient">
            <name>default</name>
            <notes/>
            <entry index="-1" color="#000000"/>
            <entry index="1" color="#ffffff"/>
        </legend>
        <legend type="gradient">
            <name>earth</name>
            <notes/>
            <entry index="-1" color="#180c49"/>
            <entry index="-0.5934959349593496" color="#3465a4"/>
            <entry index="0.04878048780487809" color="#729fcf"/>
            <entry index="0.08130081300813008" color="#4e9a06"/>
            <entry index="0.2682926829268293" color="#73d216"/>
            <entry index="0.5284552845528456" color="#c4a000"/>
            <entry index="0.7398373983739837" color="#e9b96e"/>
            <entry index="1" color="#ffffff"/>
        </legend>
    </legends>
    <model>

    </model>
</calenhad>

